# **Damian Walsh**



# Summary

Commercially aware UX/UI designer with over 15 years experience in agency and client side roles for FTSE listed companies across financial, publishing and retail sectors.

Produces user-friendly interfaces informed by research and best practices which balance user needs with business objectives.

Comfortable working across disciplines at all levels. Ability to view problems from different perspectives and accommodate views of others.

Enjoys the challenge presented by working in a fast-moving constantly evolving medium. Proactively seeks opportunities to continuously improve skills and experience.

# **Objective**

Seeking role within established digital product development team at organisation which values user-centred design and offers opportunities for professional growth.

# **Expertise**

### **User Experience Design**

Producing wireframes and interactive prototypes, conducting user research and testing.

### **Visual Design**

Establishing and working within guidelines to create consistent onbrand user interfaces.

# Front-end Development

Building scalable, modular, performance optimised responsive websites and applications.

# **Experience**

**UX/UI Designer** JUN 2012 - PRESENT

Moriyama

Freelance UX/UI Designer at Umbraco Gold Partner agency. Responsible for developing responsive website projects from concept to delivery in agile environment.

**UX/UI Designer** DEC 2008 - PRESENT

Freelance

Engagements range from developing prototypes and conducting user research through to UI design and front-end development of responsive websites.

**UX/UI Designer** SEP 2009 - MAR 2012

Sportech

Freelance UX/UI design across range of online gaming products. Developed prototypes, conducted research and user testing, produced reports and stakeholder presentations.

**Head of Design** 

MAR 2005 - DEC 2008

IG

Led team responsible for design of award-winning online trading platforms. Established consistent visual design across international range of brands and products.

DEC 2003 - MAR 2005 Senior Designer

IG

Assembled cross-functional design team during period of rapid growth. Delivered localised websites and marketing assets supporting international expansion.

DEC 2001 - DEC 2003 Web Designer

IG

Part of web team responsible for delivering financial and sport spread betting products during period when business began processing majority of transactions online.

AUG 2001 - NOV 2001 Web Designer

**Tactical Marketing Group** 

Designed websites and interactive games for clients including GlaxoSmithKline and Virgin Atlantic during three month contract at integrated marketing agency.

JUL 2000 - JUL 2001 Online Editor

Future plc

Managed design magazine website. Responsible for developing features, sourcing/creating content and engaging with audience through online channels.

NOV 1998 - JUN 2000 Web Designer

**Auto Trader UK** 

Website design and marketing asset production at leading automotive marketplace.

### **Skills**

Accessibility (WCAG/WAI-ARIA), Balsamiq Mockups, BEM, Bootstrap, Bower, Compass, CSS, Foundation, Front-end Development, Git, Grunt, Gulp, HTML, Illustrator, InDesign, Information Architecture (IA), InVision, Jekyll, jQuery, Keynote, Middleman, Omnigraffle, OOCSS, Photoshop, Prototyping, Responsive Web Design, Sass, Search Engine Optimisation (SEO), Sketch, SMACSS, SourceTree, Sublime Text, Survey Design, Susy, User Interface (UI) Design, Usability, User Testing, User Experience (UX) Design, Wireframing, Wordpress Theme Development, Yeoman

### Certifications

SEP 2014 - PRESENT Umbraco Certified Level 1 Developer

Umbraco HQ

# **Education**

SEP 1995 - MAY 1998 BA (Hons) Media Arts

University of Plymouth

SEP 1993 - MAY 1995 3 A-levels

Cadbury Sixth Form College

SEP 1990 - MAY 1993 8 GCSEs

South Bromsgrove High School

### **Interests**

Responsive web design, CSS architecture, User-centred design, Lean UX

#### References

Available on request. Page 2 of 2